zen-cart.com 2017-02-01

# Zen Cart Support - Privacy Policy

## The Zen Cart® Commitment To Privacy

**revised November 2007  
updated April 2012 to add cookie information**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, Zen Ventures, LLC (herein also referred to interchangeably as Zen Cart®) provides this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, Zen Cart® makes a link to it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

### The Information Zen Cart® Collects

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Zen Cart® web site. All information marked with an asterisk (*) is required for a particular service.

Our forums require you to register before being able to post. All of the information collected during forum registration is available to all forum members and the staff and volunteers of Zen Cart® The information collected for the forum is:

Your Name*  
Email address*  
A Username*  
a web site address, other contact methods, location, etc are all optional.

Your IP address may also be logged. IP addresses may be used in fraud prevention and/or to prosecute perpetrators of fraud or other abuses.

On some pages, you may order products, make requests, and register to receive materials. The information collected for these sections is strictly confidential and only shared with shippers, payment processors and/or selected partners as needed in order to fulfill the services you have selected to engage with us. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:

Your Name*  
Billing and Shipping Address(es)*  
Email address*  
Phone number*  
possibly Credit Card number or other payment information. If a credit card number is collected it is only securely transmitted to a 3rd-party payment gateway and your credit card number is never stored on our servers.

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient's address. The information collected for these sections is strictly confidential and only shared with shippers as needed. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are:

Recipient's Name*  
Recipient's Address*  
Phone Number*  

### Newsletters

You may optionally choose to sign up for a newsletter by entering your email address in the appropriate place on our support website. When you do so, that information is stored securely by a third-party service whom we use specifically for managing our newsletter sending and subscribership. You can always opt-out of the newsletter at any time. The only information stored about you is the information you provide, such as your email address.

### The Way Zen Cart® Uses Information

Zen Cart® uses the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

Zen Cart® uses the information you provide about someone else when placing an order only to ship the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

Zen Cart® uses return email addresses to answer Zen Cart® the email Zen Cart® receives. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties except to facilitate this exchange of email.

You can register with the Zen Cart® web site if you would like to use our forum, receive newsletters, list your site in the showcase, and/or other services. Information you submit on the Zen Cart® web site may be shared with selected partners.

Zen Cart® may use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design the Zen Cart® web site and to share with advertisers. For example, Zen Cart® may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our Zen Cart® web site, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form, but Zen Cart® would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.

Finally, Zen Cart® never uses or shares the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

#### Cookies

We use cookies on the Zen Cart support site to track user activity and to provide certain functionality. These cookies are not used by Zen Ventures, LLC for any advertising purposes.  
The following cookies are used by the Zen Cart Support Site to facilitate your login, your posting permissions, your "unread markers", your account/viewing preferences, your content subscriptions, and other features enabled by the software on our site: zcsupport_cpsession, zcsupport_lastactivity, zcsupport_lastvisit, zcsupport_password, zcsupport_sessionhash, zcsupport_thread_lastview, zcsupport_userid, zcsupport_userstyleid, editor_height, vbulletin_collapse.  
There are some additional third-party services used for monitoring and improving services provided by Zen Ventures, LLC, including but not limited to tools like Google Analytics (cookies prefixed by __utm) for statistical and performance monitoring and site tuning, Twitter (including _twitter_sess, guest_id, pid, external_referer, js, original_referer) for providing information on our site from twitter feeds, Facebook (including xs, locale, s, lu, datr, c_user) for enabling display of Facebook content within our site, and YouTube (including use_hitbox, recently_watched_video_id_list, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, ACTIVITY) for enabling display of video content within our site. These third-party services are used only to enhance our site, and the cookies they use are controlled by them. 

### The Zen Cart® Commitment To Data Security:

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, Zen Cart® has put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information Zen Cart® collects online.

### The Zen Cart® Commitment To Children's Privacy:

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, Zen Cart® never collects or maintains information at our Zen Cart® web site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our Zen Cart® web site is structured to attract anyone under 13.

### How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information:

You can access all your personally identifiable information that Zen Cart® collects online and maintains by logging in and clicking on 'My Controls' or 'My Account' in the menu. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information.

### How To Contact Us:

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please contact us.[ **Contact: Zen Cart® Team**](https://www.zen-cart.com/sendmessage.php)
